

Soohwan Kim

ALRESEARCH ENGINEER · SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

6-10, Seokye-ro 13-gil, Nowon-gu, Seoul, Rep. of KOREA

🛮 (+82) 10-4564-4668 | 🗷 kaki.brain@kakaobrain.com | 🏕 blog.naver.com/sooftware | 🖸 sooftware | 🗖 Soo-hwan

"Step by step goed a long way"

Summary.

Current AI Research Engineer at Kakao Brain. I majored in Electronic & Communication Engineering and minored in Data Science at university. My research interests include technologies for human-machine interaction, such as automatic speech recognition, speech synthesis, and natural language processing. I enjoy software development and sometimes like to write my knowledge or thoughts. I want to be helpful to others through open source. You can check my github (http://github.com/sooftware) to see what I am currently up to.

Education

Kwangwoon University

Seoul, South Korea

MAJOR B.E. IN ELECTRONIC & COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING / MINOR B.E. IN DATA SCIENCE

Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2021 (Expected)

- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5 / Total GPA: 3.70 / 4.5
- Courses: Capstone Design I-II, AI & Speech Signal Processing, Software Design, Machine Learning, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Data Structure & Algorithm, Data Mining, Network Programming, IoT System Design, Big Data Language, Big Data Processing & Application, Database, Digital Signal Processing, Statistical application, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Oriented Programming Practice, Open-Source Software, System Programming, C programming, Mobile Programming, Data Communication, Computer Network, Basic Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Electronic Circuit Theory I-II, Digital Logic, Phisics Electronic Technology, Engineering Math I-II, Probability and Irregular Signaling Theory, Probability and Statistics

Professional Experience

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

AI RESEARCH ENGINEER

Nov. 2020 - Present

- Research & Develop Speech and Natural Language Processing fields
- Develop Natural Language Processing toolkit used to conduct various NLP tasks (e.g. ASR, NMT, TTS, ..., etc.)

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

RESEARCH INTERNSHIP Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Research & Develop English, Korean and Chinese Automatic Speech Recognition models
- Development of Multilingual Speech Synthesis Model with Support for 10 Languages

Spoken Language Lab @ Sogang Univ

Mapo, Seoul

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Research End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition Models
- Research Real-time Automatic Speech Recognition Based on Kaldi Toolkit

Research Interests

Undergraduate Researcher

Speech Speech Recognition, Speech Synthesis, Voice Activity Detection, Speech Enhancement

NLP Machine Translation, Languge Model, Cross-lingual

Software Software Development, Software Architecture

Skills

Programming Python, Java, C/C++, Shell Script, SQL, Android, Arduino, Assembly, HTML

Deep Learning PyTorch, Fairseq, PyTorch Lightning

Data Analysis Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, NLTK

Publication

2020 **End-to-End Speech Recognition Models in English, Korean and Chinese**, Bachelor's Graduation Thesis

2020 KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition, arXiv pre-print

November 15, 2020 Soohwan Kim · Résumé

Project Experience

Multilingual Speech Synthesis

REPRESENTATIVE

Kakao Brain

Oct. 2020 - Nov. 2020

Representative

- Development of a speech synthesis model that supports 10 languages
- Supports for Voice-Cloning and Code-Switching

English, Korean and Chinese ASR Models Development

Kakao Brain

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Development of English, Korean and Chinese Wav2vec 2.0 Models
- Experiment for improving the speed of inference
- · Comparative experiment on accuracy / inference speed by output-unit such as Character, Grapheme and Subword

KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition

Kwangwoon University

Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2020

AUTHOR

• Currently, over 100 people are stargazer this project [link]

• Write Technical Reports in arXiv [link]

Extracurricular Activity

NLP Paper Reading Kakao Brain

GROUP MEMBER Sep. 2020 - Present

- Kakao Brain Natural Language Processing Team's weekly paper reading study
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

Technical Blog Naver Blog

WRITER Aug. 2018 - Present

- Technical posting of deep learning, programming, signal processing, paper review etc.
- Having more than 100 subscribers and an average of 200 visitors a day [link]

Speech Recognition Study Group

Kwangwoon University

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

• Study speech signal processing (Spectrogram, Mel-Scale, MFCC etc..)

• Reading a paper of speech recognition and recording its contents [link]

Teaching Experience

Samsung AI Expert Course - Speech recognition

Spoken Language Lab

TEACHING ASSISTANT

TEACHING ASSISTANT

GROUP MEMBER

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2020

· Conducted Teaching Assistant role in the Speech Recognition session

Object-Oriented Programming Practice

· Covered basic JAVA programming, Ran laboratories and had office hours every week.

Answered students' questions in person and marked assignments

Kwangwoon University Mar. 2020 - Jun. 2020

Awards & Honors

AWARDS

2020 11	1st Diago Doomiele Chaine Assessed	Kwangwoon Engineering Festival (President's Award)
7070.11	ist Place. Peoble's Unoice Award.	Kwangwoon Engineering Festival (President's Award)

2019.10 Finalist (12th Place), Naver A.I Hackathon - Speech

2019.09 Finalist, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Fall

2019.04 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Spring

2018.08 Excellence Award, Samsung Multi-Campus in Java-based Algorithm for SW Development

Honors

2020.03	School Represe	entative,	5G-based ICT	Convergence	Service Idea	Contest
---------	----------------	-----------	--------------	-------------	--------------	---------

2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.09 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

November 15, 2020 Soohwan Kim · Résumé